你好
Hello
这一节我们学习示波器
In this section we learn about oscilloscopes
和信号发生器的设置
And signal generator settings
通过这节的学习
Through the study of this section
掌握信号发生器的设置方法
Master the setting method of signal generator
了解示波器的基本功能
Understand the basic functions of oscilloscope
学习示波器的使用方法
Learn how to use oscilloscope
首先介绍一下实验仪器
First of all, introduce the experimental instruments
这是数字示波器
This is a digital oscilloscope
这是数字信号发生器
This is a digital signal generator
请大家注意一下
Please pay attention
信号线是如何连接的
How are the signal wires connected
信号发生器给两个输出
The signal generator gives two outputs
这是a输出
This is the output a
这是b输出，数字示波器有两个输通道
This is the output b, the digital oscilloscope has two output channels
这是 ch 1
This is  CH1
这是输入通道ch2
This is the input channel CH2
图中信号发生器的a输出
A output of signal generator in the figure
点到了示波器的输入通道ch 1
Point to the input channel ch 1
信号发生器的b输出
B output of signal generator
连到了示波器的通道ch2
connecting to CH2
下面介绍
Here is an introduction
数字信号发生器的设置方法
Setting method of digital signal generator
信号发生器打开之后
After the signal generator is turned on
屏幕上显示的是a输入的频率
The frequency of input A is shown on the screen
这个时候
At this time
可以对a的频率
for the frequency of A
进行设置
we can set it up
注意使用信号发生器时
Pay attention when using signal generator
输出开关要打
The output switch should be on
信号才能从信号发生器中出来
The signal comes out of the signal generator
输出开关打
Output switch on
上面的指示灯会亮
The light on it will on
设置信号参数时
When setting signal parameters
首先要进入到该参数的设置状
The first step is to enter the setting state of the parameter
比如设置电压信号时
For example, when setting the voltage signal
首先
first
要按幅度脉宽按键进入到
It is necessary to press range button to enter
电压的设置状
Voltage setting
要设置频率或者周期时
To set the frequency or period
先按频率周期按钮
firstly push the frequency/period button
进入到频率周期的设置状
Enter the setting state of frequency period
下面讲解如何设置信号电压
The following explains how to set the signal voltage
先按幅度按键
firstly push range button
进入到如图的电压设置状
Enter the voltage setting as shown in the figure
这时
At this time
我们可以设置信号的电压
We can set the voltage of the signal
设置方法是先按数
The setting method is to count first
再按单位按键
then push the unit button
看一下这两个按键
Take a look at these two buttons
底下的单位
the units at the bottom
把按键放大
Enlarge the button
shift按键对应的电压单位是
the voltage unit of under the shift button
Vpp就是Volatge
Vpp means Voltage
&quot;调频&quot;按键底下定义
FM button
是mVpp毫伏
Corresponds to mVpp
注意
be careful
设置时次序不能错
The order of setting cannot be wrong
先按数值再按单位
First by value, then by unit
下面介绍信号频率的设置方法
The setting method of signal frequency is introduced below
先按频率周期案件
First by frequency cycle
进入到频率设置状
Enter the frequency setting status
频率周期按键按一下
Press the frequency cycle button once
进入频率的设置状
Enter the setting of the frequency
才会切换到
it will switch to
周期的设置状
period setting
频率和周期是对应的
Frequency and period correspondent
设置方法是
The setting method is
先按数
Count first
再按单位
Then by unit
这三个按键对应的是频率单位
These three buttons correspond to the unit of frequency
把它放大看一下
Zoom it in
调幅底下是兆赫兹
The unit at the bottom of Tiaofu is megahertz
扫描底下是
The unit under Saomiao
千赫兹，触发底下是赫兹
is Kilohertz, unit under Chufa is hertz
注意
be careful
设置的时候次序不能错
You can't set it in the wrong order
先按数值再按单位
First by value, then by unit
设置信号的参数
Set the parameters of the signal
还有另外的方法
There's another way
大家看
Let's see
信号发生器
Signal generator
仪器上有一位数字在闪
There is a digit flashing on the instrument
我们按这两个黄色的按键
We press these two yellow buttons
闪烁的那位数字
The flashing number
可以向左移或者向右移
You can move left or right
转动圆的
Roll the cycle
旋钮
button
闪烁的那位数字会增加
The flashing number will increase
或者减少，顺时针转
Or decrease. When roll clockwise
是增加，逆时针转
It's increasing. If anti-clockwise,
是减少
It's a reduction
下面我们介绍信号发生器按键的第二功能
Next, we introduce the second function of the signal generator key
比如大家看一下
For example, let's have a look
菜单这个按键
This button
它上面画了这样一个符号
It has such a symbol on it
他代表菜单这个按键的第二功能
He represents the second function of the button
是产生锯齿波
It's a sawtooth wave
信号发生器有很多按键都有第二功能
Signal generator has a lot of cases have a second function
比如频率周期按键
For example, frequency cycle buttons
它的功能是产生正弦波
Its function is to produce sine waves
幅度脉宽按键是方波
This button is for square waves
键控是三角波
Jiankong button is for triangular waves
数字七上面有两个字
There are two words above the number seven
点频，数字八上面
Dianpin. There are two words above the number eight
有两个字
There are two words
复位
Fuwei（reset）
零下面是a输出
Below zero is output a
代表的是我们可以通过这个按键
It means that we can use this button to
切换到a输出小数点下面是b输出
Switch to output A. Below the decimal point is output B
代表通过这个按键可以切换到
Through this button, we can switch to
B
输出括号下面是移相
Below the output brackets is Yixiang (phase difference)
代表这个按键我们可以设置两个信号的巷尾差
It means we can set the phase difference of two signals
进入到按键的第二功能的方法是
The way to access the second function of a button is
先按下shift
Press &quot;shift&quot; first
再按下该按键
Press the button again
先按下shift
First press the &quot;shift&quot; button
那么
then
示波器的屏幕上会出现：
it will appear on the screen:
Shift，这个时候
&quot;shift&quot;, at this time
再按下对应的按键
Then press the corresponding key
比如说我们要设置b输出的参数
For example, we need to set the parameters of B output
怎么样切换到B输出呢？
How to switch to the output B?
先按下shift
Press &quot;shift&quot; first
再按下
Press again
小数点这个按键
The decimal point button
下面我们介绍一下
Now let's introduce it
一些按键的第二功能的设置方法
How to set the second function of some buttons
先按shift
Press shift first
再按七可以回到简单信号
Then press &quot;7&quot;, you can go back to the simple signal.
数字七上面有两个字:点频
There are two words on the number seven: Dianpin
它的意思什么呢？
What does it mean？
输出信号的频率
Frequency of output signal
是单值的
It's single
这个功能很重要
This function is very important
如果我们设置信号时
If we set the signal
按键的次序出错
Wrong order of cases
比如我按条幅
For example, I press Tiaofu
那么信号变成了调幅信号
Then the signal becomes an AM signal
先按了扫描
I pressed scan first
变得扫描信号
It becomes a scan signal
那么怎么样
So what
回到简单的信号呢
Back to the simple signal
我们可以通过按shift的
We can do this by pressing &quot;shift&quot;
在按7回到简单的正弦波
Back to the simple sine wave by pressing &quot;7&quot;
先shift再按零
Now press &quot;shift&quot; the press &quot;0&quot;
可以设置a输出的参数
You can set the parameters of output a
先按shift再按负号
First press &quot;shift&quot; then &quot;-&quot;
可以设置两个信号的相位差
You can set the phase difference of two signals
比如说先按shift
For example, now press &quot;shift&quot;
再按键控按键可以将输出信号波形变为三角波
The output signal waveform can be changed into triangle wave by pressing &quot;Jiankong&quot; button&quot;
其他的第二功能
Other second functions
以此类推
and so on
下面介绍一下示波器的一些功能
Here are some functions of the oscilloscope
使用示波器时
When using oscilloscope
先把背后的电源开关打
Turn the power switch on the back first
前面的电源指示
Front power indicator
灯会变成红色
Light will turn red
再按前面的电源按键
Press the power button again
指示灯会变成黄色
The light will turn yellow
代表示波器已经打开
It means the oscilloscope has been on
示波器的功能按键
Function buttons of oscilloscope
有如图
As shown in the picture
红色虚线方框里头
Inside the red dotted box
包括的这些
These are included
每一个按键都有相
Every button has a
对应的功能菜单
Corresponding function menu
按下这些按键时
When you press these buttons
屏幕上会出现
It will appear on the screen
对应的功能菜单
Corresponding function menu
我们举例来示范一下
Let's give an example
比如
such as
按下Hori menu
Press Hori menu
按键
button
按下这个按键之后
After pressing this button
屏幕上会出现Hori menu对应的菜单
The menu corresponding to the button will appear on the screen
这个菜单从上到下
The menu goes from top to bottom
有五个模块
There are five modules
设置这五个模块的参数
Set the parameters of these five modules
可以按旁边的五个按键
You can press the next five buttons
F1到f5
F1 to F5
比如说
for instance
要将屏幕的显示模式
To change the display mode of the screen
设置为xy模式
Set to XY mode
我们可以按下f5
We can press F5
这样
Like this
显示模式进入到xy模式
Display mode enters XY mode
示波器上有几个重要的按键
There are several important buttons on the oscilloscope
这里我们介绍一下
Here we introduce
首先是Autoset的按键
The first is the button of Autoset
这个按键是非常重要的
This button is very important
大家看一下放大的这个按键的图
Let's take a look at the enlarged picture of this button
上面写了自动设置
It says automatic settings
这个按键按下
This button is pressed
示波器会自动设置合理的显示参数
The oscilloscope will automatically set reasonable display parameters
让波形在屏幕上
Let the waveform on the screen
以最合适的状态显示出来
Display in the most appropriate state
这个按键是用的很多的一个按键
This button is an very useful button
CH 1和CH 2是输入通道的开关
CH 1 and CH 2 are input channel switches
它既是通道开关
It is a channel switch
也是按键
It also can be pressed
按一下开关打
Press the switch to turn it on
连续按两下就关掉了
Press twice to turn it off
我们以CH1为例
Let's take CH1 as an example
这个按键按下
This button is pressed
屏幕上会出现CH1的功能菜单
The function menu of CH1 will appear on the screen
功能菜单上包括
The function menu includes
耦合模式的设置
Setting of coupling mode
反向开关的设置
Setting of reverse switch
和探头的倍数等设置
And the multiple of the probe
耦合模式
Coupling mode
有三种分别是
There are three
直流，交流和接地
DC, AC and grounding
我们可以通过
We can
连续按F1在这三种
Press F1 continuously
模式之间进行切换
Switching between these three modes
大家再看一下
Let's take another look
CH1通道的指示灯是黄色的
The indicator light of CH1 channel is yellow
屏幕上
On the screen
黄色的波形
Yellow wave
是通道一的输入信号波形
Is the input signal waveform of channel one
Ch2的
CH2's
指示灯是蓝色的
The light is blue
屏幕上蓝色的波形
The blue wave on the screen
是通道二的输入信号产生的波形
It is the waveform generated by the input signal of channel 2
下面介绍示波器的旋钮的功能
The following describes the function of the oscilloscope knobs
这些旋钮可以调节示波器的显示参数
These knobs can adjust the display parameters of the oscilloscope
我们举例说一下
Let's give an example
这是通道一的垂直挡位旋钮
This is the vertical knob of channel one
这是通道二的垂直挡位旋钮
This is the vertical knob for channel two
这个旋钮调节扫速开关的档位
This knob adjusts the gears of scan rate
这三个参数
These three parameters
是什么意义呢
What's the point
下面我们来进行解读
Now let's interpret it
如图波形
As shown in the figure
水平方向
horizontal direction
是按照时间来进行展开的
It is carried out according to time
垂直方向代表的是电压
The vertical direction represents the voltage
扫速开关档位
Scan rate switch gear
它是指波形沿水平方向
It refers to the waveform along the horizontal direction
是按时间展开的
It's time
每一大格代表的时间是多少
What is the time of each grid
这个参数究竟是多少
What is the parameter
在屏幕上的这个位置
In this position on the screen
会有显示
There will be a display
它代表的意思
What does it mean
大家看屏幕上有网格线
Look, there are gridlines on the screen
当前水平方向一大
The current horizontal direction is a big one
代表的时间是
What is the representative's time
100微秒
100 ms
就是说每一
That is to say, every grid
代表的是100微秒的时间
represents 100 microseconds
我们测量信号的周期时
We measure the period of the signal
可以用到
You can use it
通道一和通道二的垂直档位
Vertical gear of channel 1 and channel 2
代表的是波形沿垂直方向展开的时候
It represents the time when the waveform expands vertically
每一大格代表的电压
Each grid represents the voltage
具体的参数在
The specific parameters are
屏幕的右下角这个位置
In the lower right corner of the screen
显示出来
Show it
如图
As shown in the picture
我们可以看到
We can see that
通道一的波形
Waveform of channel one
垂直方向展
Vertical expansion
每一格代表的电压
Each grid represents the voltage
是五伏，通道二
Is 5V. Channel two
波形垂直方向展开
The broadcast line is expanded vertically
每隔代表的电压是一伏
The voltage represented by each interval is 1 volt
我们在
We are here
进行信号电压测量时
When measuring the signal voltage
可以用到本次讲解
You can use this explanation
到此结束
That's the end
谢谢
thank you